<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course Logistics on MLOps: Operationalizing Machine Learning</title>
    <link>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Course Logistics on MLOps: Operationalizing Machine Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Learning Details</title>
      <link>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/online_technology_requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/online_technology_requirements/</guid>
      <description>Online Learning Details To maximize the learning experience, it will be good if students can meet the following basic technology requirements:
 At a minimum, students should have a device and an internet connection. A microphone, and a webcam would be highly recommended. See the Basic Technology Requirements link for more details.
 Laptop, Chromebook or Desktop Computer: Note that Chromebooks are used to perform a variety of browser-based tasks with most data and applications, such as Blackboard Learn, Blackboard Collaborate, Google Docs, and Office 365, residing in the cloud rather than on the machine itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Textbook  Data Science in Production by Ben Weber (2020, $5 for the ebook/pdf). A sample of the first three chapters is available at the publishers page linked here.  Lecture Schedule Lecture 1: Serving ML Models Using Web Servers Reference: Chapter 2  Learning Goals:  Be able to set up a Python environment Be able to set up a jupyter session with SSH tunneling Be able to secure a web server Be able to use Flask to serve a ML model   Lecture 2: Serving ML Models Using Serverless Infrastructure Reference: Chapter 3  Learning Goals:  Be able to differentiate hosted vs managed solutions Assess deops effort for web server vs serverless deployments Be able to deploy a ML model using Google Cloud Functions and AWS Lambda Functions   Lecture 3: Serving ML Models Using Docker Reference: Chapter 4, upto 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/project_instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chicagodatascience.github.io/MLOps/logistics/project_instructions/</guid>
      <description>Aim  The aim of the project is to simulate the real-world process of deploying machine learning models. More specifically, the project component of this course allows you to explore a technology that assists in model deployment, either directly or indirectly, and asks you to report your experience working with that technology (or multiple technologies) to achieve some overall deployment goal.  Group  You should form groups of 4 students for this project component (this is a strict requirement).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>